riffsy.com 2019-06-29

# Tenor Privacy Policy

### Effective Date: March 10, 2018

Tenor (“Tenor”, “we,” “us,” or “our”) is committed to respecting the privacy of your personal information as a user of our mobile and desktop applications and extensions (the “Apps”) or a visitor to our website (the “Site”) and the associated services, including the our services provided by us through third party offerings, such as social networks or messaging applications (our Apps, the Site and the associated services are collectively called the “Services”).

This Privacy Policy explains what information Tenor collects from users of its Services and how we may use that information and addresses related questions. By registering for an online account with us, or using any of our Services, you agree and consent to this Privacy Policy. The Tenor Terms of Service at  https://tenor.com/legal-terms contain additional terms and conditions governing your use of the Services.

### Overview of the Tenor Services

Tenor provides Apps which users can use to insert GIFs and videos into messages, posts and web pages within messaging applications, email clients or other ways of communication and messaging. Tenor’s Apps also include alternative keyboards for mobile devices and input extensions on mobile devices and computers, which may be activated by hotkey or otherwise contextually activated. The Tenor Apps may access information on your device in order to function, but that information is not transmitted to or collected by Tenor, except as stated in this Privacy Policy.

Tenor also provides Services to allow third party offerings such as social networks, messaging networks, and other applications (such as dating applications and games) to integrate GIFs and videos into the messaging interfaces of those third party offerings, without separately installing a Tenor App.

Tenor does not collect information that a user enters into the text entry field of their device unless the user has invoked the Tenor App, which will be clearly indicated when using the Tenor App. Upon invocation, the Tenor Apps will either use the text entry field as a search input area or will present a separate search input area to search for GIFs and videos. Tenor does, as described in this Privacy Policy, collect information that a user enters into the input area for searching Tenor’s content library.

When you install the Tenor App on your iOS device, you will be asked to provide the App with "Full Access", which means that the Tenor App will have full access to the internet, which is necessary for Tenor to respond to search requests and to deliver GIFs and videos to you. Tenor does not log keystrokes or send them to our servers other than to search by key terms for the GIF and videos relevant to your search requests. Nevertheless, Apple displays its standard warning about "Full Access" whenever you grant it.

When you install the Tenor App on your Android device, you will be asked to provide the App with permission to use the Accessibility Settings, which the Tenor App requires in order to insert GIFs and videos into your messages. The Tenor App will also require internet access, which is necessary for Tenor to respond to search requests and to deliver GIFs and videos to you. Tenor does not log keystrokes or send them to our servers other than to search by key terms for GIF and videos relevant to your search requests.

### Information that Tenor Avoids Collecting

Tenor recommends you use your device’s standard keyboard whenever entering credit card numbers, passwords or other sensitive information. If you enter any of this information into the Tenor’s content library search input area, Tenor will receive it. We use reasonable efforts to remove this type of information from our records, but cannot guarantee that we will be able to do so.

### What Information Does Tenor Collect About Me and Why?

If you use an App:

We may collect:

| 

Why we collect it and how we use it:  
  
---|---  
  
Your device’s App identifier (We generate and store a unique identifier for the App on your device when you first use an App on your device)

| 

  * To show you which devices and Apps are authorized to access your online account and to respond to your inquiries
  * To provide App updates
  * To provide support to you
  * To optimize the results of your searches for content using the App
  * To calculate statistics such as the number of unique devices using our Apps and services
  * As indicated in the section below titled “Use of Information in Advertising”

Your IP address

| 

  * To return the results of your searches of our Content library using the App
  * To manage our Services and protect them from security threats
  * To provide localized search results and localized notifications and content
  * As indicated in the section below titled “Use of Information in Advertising”

A history of the Content viewed in our Content library, associated with the IP address requesting such Content

| 

  * To optimize the results of your searches for content using the App
  * To be able to notify you about content in which you may be interested
  * To manage our Apps, and services, to improve our products and services and to create new products and services
  * Aggregated with other similar data to calculate statistics
  * As indicated in the section below titled “Use of Information in Advertising”

A history of the search terms you enter

| 

  * To optimize the results of your searches for content using the App
  * To be able to notify you about content in which you may be interested
  * To manage our Apps, and services, to improve our products and services and to create new products and services
  * Aggregated with other similar data to calculate statistics
  * As indicated in the section below titled “Use of Information in Advertising”

Information about the operation and use of the Apps, such as:

  * Information about your use of the App, such as the number of images or videos on which the App acts, search terms you enter into the App, categories of content you share with the App
  * Information about actions you perform in the App, including analyzing your interaction with the user interface, timing and statistics of functions performed by the App
  * Error and diagnostic information about the App and your device

| 

  * To provide support to you.
  * To optimize the results of your searches for Content using the App
  * Aggregated with other similar data to manage our Apps, and services, to improve our products and services and to create new products and services
  * Aggregated with other similar data to calculate statistics
  * As indicated in the section below titled “Use of Information in Advertising”

Your feedback (if you provide it)

| 

  * To hear and understand your concerns and suggestions.
  * To manage our Services, to improve our products and services and to create new products and services.

Analytic information

| 

Please see the section below titled “Does Tenor Use Cookies or Collect Analytic Information About Me or My Devices?”  
  
Information related to your interaction with advertising

| 

In addition to the section below titled “Does Tenor Use Cookies or Collect Analytic Information About Me or My Devices?”, please also see the section below titled “Use of Information in Advertising”  
  
If you use our Service as part of a third party offering:

We may collect:

| 

Why we collect it:  
  
---|---  
  
The identity of the third party offering through which you access our Service

| 

  * To calculate statistics such as the number of unique devices and third party offerings using our Apps and Services
  * As indicated in the section below titled “Use of Information in Advertising”

Your IP address

| 

  * To return the results of your searches of our Content library using the Service
  * To manage our Services and protect them from security threats
  * To provide localized search results and localized content
  * As indicated in the section below titled “Use of Information in Advertising”

A history of the Content viewed in our Content library, associated with the IP address requesting such Content

| 

  * To optimize the results of your searches for content using the App
  * To manage our Apps, and Services, to improve our products and services and to create new products and services
  * Aggregated with other similar data to calculate statistics
  * As indicated in the section below titled “Use of Information in Advertising”

A history of the search terms you enter

| 

  * To optimize the results of your searches for content using the App
  * To manage our Apps, and services, to improve our products and services and to create new products and services
  * Aggregated with other similar data to calculate statistics
  * As indicated in the section below titled “Use of Information in Advertising”

Information about the operation and use of the Services, such as:

  * Information about your use of the Services, such as the number of images or videos on which the Service acts, search terms you enter into the Service, categories of content you share with the Service
  * Error and diagnostic information about the Service and your device

| 

  * To provide support to you.
  * To optimize the results of your searches for content using the App
  * Aggregated with other similar data to manage our Apps, and services, to improve our products and services and to create new products and services
  * Aggregated with other similar data to calculate statistics
  * As indicated in the section below titled “Use of Information in Advertising”

GIFs/Videos you have elected to store on our systems or synchronize across multiple devices; tags you have elected to add to those GIFs/Videos

| 

Please see the section below titled “What Happens to the GIFs and Videos that I Upload to Tenor?”  
  
Your feedback (if you provide it)

| 

  * To hear and understand your concerns and suggestions.
  * To manage our Services, to improve our products and services and to create new products and services.

Analytic information

| 

Please see the section below titled “Does Tenor Use Cookies or Collect Analytic Information About Me or My Devices?”  
  
Information related to your interaction with advertising

| 

In addition to the section below titled “Does Tenor Use Cookies or Collect Analytic Information About Me or My Devices?”, please also see the section below titled “Use of Information in Advertising”  
  
If you create, register, or log into an Account through our App or Site:

We may collect:

| 

Why we collect it:  
  
---|---  
  
Your username, email address, first name, last name, and contact preferences

| 

  * To create and support your online account and use of the Services.
  * To communicate with you, including for technical support and to respond to your inquiries.
  * To send you a very limited number of marketing emails and offers (unless you opt-out).
  * To share with other Users and with the public if you choose to make this information visible (which occurs when you “Publish” GIFs or Videos as we explain below).

Your Social Network user name or user ID and certain personal information, such as your name and email address, and other personal information that your Social Network account privacy settings permit us to access. Please check the Social Network policies and your privacy settings in order to understand what information we receive.

| 

  * So that your identity can be authenticated by the Social Network if you use certain third-party Social Networks, such as Facebook, to create an Account.
  * For the same purposes that we collect your username, email address, first name, last name, and contact preferences if you create an Account with us directly.
  * To share with other Users and with the public if you choose to make this information visible (which occurs when you “Publish” GIFs or Videos as we explain below).

GIFs/Videos you have elected to store on our systems or synchronize across multiple devices; tags you have elected to add to those GIFs/Videos

| 

Please see the section below titled “What Happens to the GIFs and Videos that I Upload to Tenor?”  
  
Other information you may choose to place in your Account profile

| 

To share with other Users and with the public if you make this information visible (which occurs when you “Publish” GIFs or Videos as we explain below).  
  
Analytic information

| 

Please see the section below titled “Does Tenor Use Cookies or Collect Analytic Information About Me or My Devices?”  
  
If you visit our Sites (whether or not you have created an Account):

We may collect:

| 

Why we collect it:  
  
---|---  
  
Your feedback (if you provide it)

| 

  * To hear and understand your concerns and suggestions.
  * To manage our Services, and services, to improve our products and services and to create new products and services.

Web browser information (e.g., the URLs you visited; your IP address; date, time, and time spent on pages visited; and information about your browser and platform)

| 

  * To remember your information so that you do not need to re-enter it when using the Sites, and provide personalized content.
  * To assist in identifying Site visitors so that we may more effectively respond to their inquiries.
  * To manage our Services, to improve our products and services and to create new products and services.
  * As indicated in the section below titled “Use of Information in Advertising”

Analytic information

| 

Please see the section below titled “Does Tenor Use Cookies or Collect Analytic Information About Me or My Devices?”  
  
Information related to your interaction with advertising

| 

In addition to the section below titled “Does Tenor Use Cookies or Collect Analytic Information About Me or My Devices?”, please also see the section below titled “Use of Information in Advertising”  
  
### What Happens to the GIFs and Videos that I Upload to Tenor?

You may upload GIFs and Videos to Tenor through the Tenor Apps and Site. When you upload a GIF or Video, the GIF is "Personal" and is initially stored on your device for use later on that device. Once you create an account and log in to your account, your GIFs and Videos will be stored in Tenor's service and your GIFs and Videos will be available on any other devices logged into that account. If you decide to add a tag or tags to your GIF or Video, your GIF or Video, along with the associated tags, will be submitted to Tenor for review and, if approved, will become part of the Tenor content library and "Published" for use by other users of the Tenor Services. If you added a tag or tags to your GIFs or Videos prior to logging into your account, the GIF and Videos, and the associated tags, will be automatically submitted to Tenor upon logging into your account. Do not tag GIFs or Videos if you do not wish them to be Published and associated with your Account profile. When your GIF or Video is Published, it will be available to other users of the Tenor Services, your username and other Account profile information will be displayed alongside the GIF or Video, and Tenor users will be able to search for other GIFs and Videos you have uploaded based on your username.

GIFs and Videos are not encrypted or hosted on a private URL, which means it is possible for others to figure out how to access your GIFs and Videos, even if Personal. Do not store any GIFs or Videos on Tenor that you do not wish others to be able to access or which you do not wish others to be able to associate with you.

### Account Profiles

As part of our Services, Users may, including by Publishing User Content or creating published collections of Content, display their Account profile to other Users and to the public. We encourage you to use your good judgment about what you place in your Account profile and not to post any private or sensitive information.

### Does Tenor Use Cookies or Collect Analytic Information About Me Or My Devices?

We use cookies, tracking pixels and similar technologies on our Sites, Apps and emails (including in GIFs/Videos)to collect and use information that helps us provide our Services to you. Cookies are a feature of browsers that enable websites to store a small piece of data on your device when you visit them. Tracking pixels are small graphic images embedded in email messages or in advertisements and sponsored content to track user interaction with email messages were opened and to track the views, actions and other performance statistics regarding advertising and sponsored content.

We use cookies to remember your information and preferences so that you do not need to re-enter them (e.g., to remember whether you are logged in), to provide personalized content, and to help us provide the Services to you (such as the ability to submit feedback to us). We also use cookies and similar technologies to help us understand how you use the emails and Services, and whether and when you view GIFS/Videos, so that we can more effectively communicate with you and improve our offerings, and as described in the section below titled “Use of Information in Advertising”. These technologies can give us insights such as how you arrived at our Sites, how long you stayed and which pages you visited. We use analytics technologies from third parties such as Google Analytics. (For Google’s privacy practices see  <https://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html> and to opt out of data recording and analysis by Google Analytics on our Sites, see  <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.)

You can choose whether to accept cookies by changing the settings on your web browser. Major mobile operating systems also enable you to limit certain online functionality and data collection. However, if you disable these functions, your experience with our offerings may be significantly limited. If you choose not to receive tracking pixels in your emails, you will need to disable HTML images in your email program, but that may affect images in other emails you receive.

We may also collect advertising identifiers from your mobile device. Advertising identifiers are resettable identifiers unique to your mobile device, and which are used in connection with advertising delivered to your mobile device. Examples of advertising identifiers include IDFA (developed by Apple for the iPhone) and Google Ad ID (developed by Google for Android). Advertising identifiers are used to provide targeted advertising and otherwise for the purposes described in the section below titled “Collection and Use of Advertising-related Information”. If you don’t want advertising identifiers to be used to provide targeted advertising to you, see the section below titled “Can I Opt Out of Targeted Advertising?”

### Use of Information in Advertising

We may use the Services to provide advertisements and/or sponsored GIFs/Videos that are likely to be more interesting and more relevant to users. One way we may do this is by collecting information related to users, which may include elements like the search terms you have provided to the Service, GIFs/Videos you have shared or viewed, preferences that you may have provided to us, advertising identifiers, or location information (i.e. GPS or Wi-Fi data if you have enabled those services). 

We may also use the information we have collected through the Services in order to:

  * Measure the performance of advertising campaigns and/or sponsored GIFs/Videos, whether displayed within our Services or through third party publishers, web sites, mobile applications, and other properties;
  * Limit the number of times a specific advertisement is presented to the same browser or mobile device (frequency capping);
  * Create customized performance reports (for example, how well a particular advertisement or sponsored GIF/Video is performing in a particular geographic region or among a particular demographic); and
  * Improve the targeting or relevance of advertising and/or sponsored GIFs/Videos to users; and
  * Provide non-personally identifiable information to our advertisers or content sponsors to report to them with respect any of the foregoing.

### Can I Opt Out of Targeted Advertising?

If you wish to "opt out" of certain advertising targeted using the types of techniques described above, you have several choices:

  * Visit  [www.networkadvertising.org/choices](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices) or  [www.aboutads.info/choices/](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/).
  * Reset your mobile device’s advertising identifier or set it to opt out of targeted advertising.
    * Android: You can reset your advertising ID at any time, right from the Ads section of the Google Settings app on your device. From the same app, you can also opt-out of targeted advertising based on the advertising ID by setting the appropriate ad tracking preference.
    * iOS: You can opt out of targeted advertising by electing Limit Ad Tracking in your device’s settings menu (as of the date of this Privacy Policy, located at Settings > Privacy > Advertising).

You should be aware that if you “opt out” it does not mean that you will no longer receive advertising. It just means that the advertising you see displayed will not be customized to you and your interests and may be less relevant to you.

### Do Not Track

Our Site does not have the capability to respond to “Do Not Track” signals received from various web browsers.

### Will Tenor Contact Me?

If you have provided us with your email address, from time to time, we may want to contact you by email with information about product announcements, software updates and offers. By accepting this Privacy Policy, you accept our offer to send you these emails. You may opt-out of such communications at any time by following the instructions within our emails.

We may send you certain service, support and administrative notices, even if you have opted-out from promotional emails. Also, we may contact you in response to your request.

### Does Tenor Share My Personal Information?

We do not sell, rent or otherwise share your personally identifiable information with any third parties except in the following limited circumstances;

  * If you upload User Content to our systems to be Published or otherwise shared with another user of our Service or if you Publish Content Collections, your Account name and profile will be associated with the User Content you upload, will be visible to anyone who views the User Content you have uploaded, and may be visible to the public. In addition to any information you may elect to place in your Account profile, your Account profile will also include certain information regarding your use of the Service, including but not limited to Content collections you have Published, number of other Users you follow, and the number of Users who follow you.
  * We need to share your information with our service providers or our affiliated companies in order to provide and distribute the Apps and their functions, the Sites, our other Services, and related services and support; to complete billing and payment for them; or to collect information and communicate with you as described above.
  * We determine that we need to comply with any law, regulation or order, such as a subpoena, court order or search warrant, or to apply or enforce our terms of service or other agreements or protect the rights, property and personal safety of our users, visitors, company, or others.
  * We do so in connection with the transfer, sale, merger or reorganization of all or any relevant portion of our business or assets to or with any third party.
  * We have your explicit permission or opt-in to share your information.

### How Can I Correct Information that Tenor Has About Me?

If you would like to correct any personal information that we hold about you, you may update your information in the user settings of your online Account (to the extent that functionality is available) or email us per “How Can I Contact Tenor?” below. For marketing emails, you may also follow the instructions in the email to opt-out.

### Where is My Information Stored?

Through your use of the Services, all personal information collected via or by Tenor may be stored anywhere in the world, including but not limited to, in the United States, in the cloud, on our servers, on the servers of our affiliates or the servers of our service providers. Your personal information may be accessible to law enforcement or other authorities pursuant to a lawful request. If you are visiting from the European Union or other regions with laws governing data collection and use, please note that you are agreeing to the transfer of your information to the United States and processing globally. By providing your personal information, you consent to any transfer and processing in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

### How Secure is My Information with Tenor?

Protecting the security of your information is important to us. We use commercially reasonable actions to protect your information, including security measures in the Services to prevent loss, misuse, and alteration of your information. However, we cannot assure against any such loss, misuse, or alteration. The security of information stored locally on your device depends on your use of security functionality on that device. So, we recommend that you protect against unauthorized access to your passwords and devices.

### What if this Privacy Policy Changes?

Changes in our products and services, our business and laws may require us to change this Privacy Policy. We may change this Privacy Policy by posting a revised version on the Sites and/or an update in the Apps, and/or by sending information regarding the change to your e-mail address in our records. We suggest that you regularly review the Apps and/or Sites to learn about any changes. By continuing to use the Services after such changes have been posted or sent to you means that you agree to such changes. If you do not agree to such changes, you may stop all access and use of the Services.

### Does Tenor Collect and Use Information from Children?

We do not offer or sell products or services for use by children under the age of 13. Further, if you are under 18, you may use our products and services only with the involvement of a parent or guardian.

### When Would Other Privacy Policies Apply?

The Apps, Sites and content in or on them may contain links to other sites and resources controlled by third parties or may need you to install third party functionality. Also, as discussed above, the Tenor Apps or Services may allow you to integrate GIFs and Videos into the messaging interfaces of third party services. We do not control the privacy practices or content of any third party other sites, services, resources or functionality, and you should consult the privacy statements of those third parties. Also, we may engage third party ad server companies whose policies may govern access to any ads or links made available to you.

### How Can I Contact Tenor?

You may contact us at [support@tenor.com](mailto:support@tenor.com) or at the address below. Your submissions to us are subject to this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Service at https://tenor.com/legal-terms.
